For the past few days, I've been
exploring different workflow from Figma
to cursor and cloud code to get a
generate super hype daily UI based on
the Figma mo as well as this new chassen
MCP that allow you to access different
source of UI component libraries. So you
can get a generally sophisticated UI
animations and components from all sorts
of different styles instead of just the
default chassis in and I'm going to talk
you through this workflow in just 5
minutes. The effectiveness of Figma MCP
can't exceed my expectation. I can take
a pretty sophisticated design like this,
copy link to selection and just go back
to cursor or cloud code, ask it to
implement landing page section 100%
pixel perfect and the cool part is that
the Figma MCP tool also allow you to
download image and SVG assets. Then it
will generates almost pixel perfect
design. Obviously there will be some
like difference and I can just copy
paste over. I can give it a prompt.
Overall looks great. Just make two
changes. one image and it says on the
right side should have some color
background and there should be border
line between the left and right section.
Great. You can see the left side is
original Figma mo, the right side is UI
generated. Looks almost 100% pixel
perfect within just two prompts. And all
that is thanks to this awesome Figma MCP
made by RAM is open source. The real
killer feature in my mind is this
download Figma image feature allow you
to just download both image assets as
SVG logos. And to install this MCP tool,
you can just put this MCP to your cursor
or cloud code. So you need to replace
your uh Figma API key here. And to get
Figma API key, you can just go to Figma,
click on settings, security, and
generate new personal access token. You
can set expiration date to be a bit
longer, give a name, and probably just
give access to most of those stuff,
especially read permission for your
files and then generate this token,
paste over here. Meanwhile, another
really cool MCP tool you can try is this
new chassen MCP server. So this tool
allow you to connect any of those
chassis based UI component library which
means there will be more than just
chassen. There could be new UI component
library built upon chassen as different
style that you can just connect to like
chassen form tark and magic UI. And
what's really cool about this MCP server
is that it will help you retrieve
whatever component available in each UI
component library that we import there
and automatically retrieve the command
line to add those relevant components
and blocks to your project and get
example code of how to use those
components. And the best thing is that
if you're designing Figma is already
using chassen based components with
correct naming then between the Figma
MCP and chassen MCP you can almost
design 100% pixel perfect UI. And to do
that you first need a project that has
chassen set up already. Then you can run
this MPX chassen latest MCP initiate
with a specific client you are using. If
you're using cursor you can run this but
also cloud code and VS code. And once
you run that should add the chassis and
MCP to your pure level. So this is very
important. This MCP service need to be
per level because it will read the UI
components library that you imported in
the registries. And meanwhile you're
also adding this agents.mmd file to add
additional rules about how agent should
be using those tools. If you set up the
chassen public there should be a
components.json file and you will need
to add registries. So those registries
are new UI component library built upon
chassen and they will all follow similar
structure as URL where they host this UI
component library and / r which
represent for registry the JSON file
that including the component. If you
don't have your chassen um like template
already set up, upload that to MCP
classrooms chassen MCP and Figma MCP
session. So you can download and use and
just customize the registries part. So
here I have both a Figma MCP and chassis
MCP and activate it and I can just do
the same thing. Go to the Figma. Copy
the link to the selection of frame where
we use chassen components. Paste in from
help me review this UI from Figma using
chassen to be 100% pixel perfect.
Retrieve the data from Figma. Check all
the UI component library already
connected to this project and search for
relevant component for data table
badges and cards based on the Figma
layer names. Add those components.
Create the UI. So now this is UI
generated from just one shot and you
just compare with what's in Figma side
by side almost look 100% pixel perfect.
So this basically power of chassis and
MCP plus the Figma MCP for you to get
really fine-tuned pixel perfect UI but
the power of this chassis and MCP is not
just there. The really interesting part
is this ability to allow agent search
components across different registries
and automatic import download to use
those examples. And let me demonstrate
this. At moment, there's no directory of
public registries that you can use
directly. There's a few I found online
that is pretty cool. including this
fancy component that's specialized in
all the different animations to this
animate UI that has all the like
animation that it added as well as this
one that focus on kind of chat UI where
I give you things like modal selectors
and this one that has a whole bunch of
really cool stuff and and also there are
specialized shing component like focus
on just one thing like text editor that
provide a whole bunch of things that
allow you to build all sort of different
text editor experience. So as an example
I can just add those components registry
in and for the ones we test we use PL UI
I can ask what's in PL UI it will check
the components a list of useful
components inside this library then I
can just ask it to help me build a text
editor UI then it will start adding the
components and build up the UI. If you
check out it will add all those
component directly into your project. If
we check out now we have this pretty
sophisticated text editor experience
directly implemented. you can swap out
to a different library to add some like
fancy animation to make this UI look
better as well. So you can mix match
different components. So this is the
power of the new chassis MCP and you can
even build your own UI component library
hosted somewhere so you can import for
your future purchase. If you're
interested about that, I can also make a
video talking about it. So comment below
if you want to learn more. I have added
all detailed instructions to AI builder
club about all the MCP tool that we talk
about as well as a chassis invite
template that already have this
component registry set up. So you can
come just modify, edit and start using
right away. Meanwhile, we run weekly
workshop talking about the latest tips
and workflows of vibe code in
production. And this upcoming week's
workshop, we're going to specifically
talk about UI generation workflow. So if
you're interested, you can click on the
link below to join AI builder club in
our upcoming weekly session. I hope this
is useful. Thank you and I see you next